<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-66</Accession>
        <Title>Mohenjo-Daro:  Plan of Lower Town Grid</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: Mohenjo-daro was built in the 26th century BCE and was one of the largest cities of the ancient Indus Valley Civilization, also known as the Harappan Civilization. It was the most advanced city of its time, with remarkably sophisticated civil engineering and urban planning. Mohenjo-daro has a planned layout based on a street grid of rectilinear buildings. The sheer size of the city, and its provision of public buildings and facilities, suggests a high level of social organization. The city is divided into two parts, the so-called Citadel and the Lower City (seen in this image).  | Location created: Mohenjo-Daro Site (Pakistan) | Date created: 2500-1600 B CE | Current location: Mohenjo-Daro | Medium: X | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>-1600</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Architecture--Pakistan  | City planning--Pakistan | Cities and towns, Ancient</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Mohenjo-Daro Site (Pakistan)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Mohenjo-daro | Harappan |  urban planning</Genre>
        <Century>17th century BCE</Century>
        <Spatial>Mohenjo-Daro Site (Pakistan)</Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-67</Accession>
        <Title>Young Dancer</Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Dancing Girl of Mohenjo-Daro</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: This sculpture is from the ancient city of Mohenjo-Daro, now in present day Pakistan. The statue indicates two important aspects about the civilization: first, that entertainment, especially dance, was part of the culture. Although the figure is in standing position, it was named "Dancing Girl" with an assumption of her profession. The girl is naked, wears a number of bangles and a necklace, and is shown in a natural standing position with one hand on her hip. Secondly, the bronze statue is important because it was made using the lost-wax casting technique; this shows the expertise of the people in making bronze works during that time. | Location created: Mohenjo-daro | Date created: c. 2500 BCE | Current location: National Museum, New Delhi, Delhi | Medium: Bronze | Measurements: 10.5 cm  × 5 cm  (4 1/8 in  × 2 in )</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>-2500</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Bronze sculpture, Ancient | Lost wax casting</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Mohenjo-Daro Site (Pakistan)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Mohenjo-daro | Harappan | statues | bronze (metal) | lost-wax process</Genre>
        <Century>24th century BCE</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-68</Accession>
        <Title>Lion Capital inscribed shaft stump</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: This image shows the inscription on the surviving base of the Ashokan pillar. The Brahmin inscription on the Ashoka main pillars indicate the spot where Lord Buddha preached his first sermon. King Ashoka erected pillar to commemorate his visit in 3rd century BC. The third emperor of the Mauryan dynasty, Ashoka, who ruled from c. 279 B.C.E. - 232 B.C.E., was the first leader to accept Buddhism and thus the first major patron of Buddhist art.   | Location created: Sarnath | Date created: 3rd century BCE | Current location: X | Medium: Stone | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>-232</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Sculpture, Maurya | Buddhist sculpture--India | Columns--India</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sārnāth Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>monumental pillars</Genre>
        <Century>3rd century BCE</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-69</Accession>
        <Title>Exterior view of Chaitya Hall, Bhaja Caves </Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Bhaja: Chaitya general view</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: At Bhaja Caves, south of Karli, there are more than 20 rock-cut Buddhist structures from the Satavahana period, the earliest phase of Buddhist rock-cut architectural activity. The Great Chaitya or prayer hall (Cave XII) dates from the 2nd century BC. The Chaitya would have served as a centre of religious practice for the monks who lived in the adjacent rock-cut monastery or vihara. Monks were not allowed to possess material wealth, and inscriptions at this temple, and others, indicate that the construction of Chaityas was funded through donations from merchants and landowners. Bhaja is widely regarded as the earliest example of a mature Chaitya plan, with a nave, columns and side aisles. The temple would have also incorporated a vaulted roof with teak beams and a wooden facade however both features have now perished. Inside the apsidal-ended hall the nave and aisles are separated by octagonal columns and a hemispherical stupa is situated at the far end. | Location created: India | Date created: c. 2nd century BCE | Current location: Pune district, India | Medium: Basalt | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>-100</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist cave temples--India | Buddhist architecture</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Bhājā Caves (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>stupas | cave temples</Genre>
        <Century>2nd century BCE</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-70</Accession>
        <Title>Interior view of Chaitya Hall, Bhaja Caves</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description:  The chaitya at Bhaja Caves consists of an apsidal hall with stupa. The stone columns slope inwards to imitate wooden columns that would have been structurally necessary to keep a roof up. The ceiling is barrel vaulted with wooden ribs set into them. The walls were polished in the Mauryan style. It was faced by a substantial wooden facade. A large horseshoe-shaped window, the "chaitya-window," was set above the arched doorway and the whole portico-area was carved to imitate a multi-storeyed building with balconies and windows and sculptured men and women who observed the scene below. This created the appearance of an ancient Indian mansion. In Bhaja, as in other chaityas, the entrance acted as the demarcation between the sacred and the profane. The stupa inside the hall was  completely removed from the sight of anyone outside. | Location created: India | Date created: First or second century BCE | Current location: Pune district, India | Medium: Basalt | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>-100</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist cave temples--India Buddhist architecture</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Bhājā Caves (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>stupas | cave temples</Genre>
        <Century>2nd century BCE</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-71</Accession>
        <Title>Great Stupa of Sanchi, Elevation View of Building</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The Great Stupa at Sanchi, in central India, is one of the earliest stupas; it served as an architectural prototype for all others that followed. In this plan, we see the torana (A), balustrade (D &amp; E), dome or "anda" (F), harmika (H), yasti and chattras (I), and stairs (L).  The dome, or "anda," symbolizes the universe. | Location created: India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: X | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist temples | Buddhist architecture</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>stupas | temples (buildings)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial>Sānchi Site (India)</Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-72</Accession>
        <Title>Great Stupa of Sanchi, Plan</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The Great Stupa at Sanchi, in central India, is one of the earliest stupas; it served as an architectural prototype for all others that followed. The floor plan of the Great Stupa symbolizes a cosmic diagram. | Location created: India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: X | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist temples | Buddhist architecture</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>stupas | temples (buildings)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial>Sānchi Site (India)</Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-73</Accession>
        <Title>Scene from Eastern Gateway at Great Stupa of Sanchi</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: This image shows a scene carved in sandstone relief on the Eastern Gateway (torana), North Pillar at the Great Stupa at Sanchi. Towards the top half of the image, we see the scene that depicts the dream of Maya, the mother of the historical Buddha. Queen Maya is asleep in her palace under a full moon. An attendant stands guard outside. In her dream, a white elephant enters her side. This is a miraculous conception that results in the birth of the future Buddha. | Location created: Madhya Pradesh, India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: Sandstone | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture)</Subject>
        <personalNames>Queen Maya</personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>toranas | reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-74</Accession>
        <Title>Scene from the Eastern Gateway (front) architraves at Great Stupa of Sanchi</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The upper scene on the East torana (exterior middle architrave) of Stupa 1 (The Grand Stupa) at Sanchi depicts the Future Buddha's Great Departure--when he renounced his royal status and became a homeless wanderer searching for supreme enlightenment. Motifs such as wheels, thrones, and footprints are used to symbolize the Buddha, who is not represented in human form until later.  The lower scene, from the lowest torana arch of the eastern gateway shown above, depicts the emperor Ashoka's visit to the Bodhi tree in Bodh Gaya, the site of the Buddha's enlightenment.  Ashoka's piety is visible not only from his visits to these holy sites, but in his patronage in establishing sites such as Sanchi itself.  Such public acts of piety were also good public relations moves, since they placed Ashoka in the role of the righteous king, but it seems clear from various sorts of evidence that at a personal level Ashoka was a pious Buddhist. Here the tree (itself a symbol for the Buddha) is in the center, and around it stand Ashoka and his court making appropriate reverential gestures.  One of Ashoka's wives from Vidisha--which is only 6 miles away, so he had strong connections to the region, and good reasons to spread patronage there. | Location created: Madhya Pradesh, India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: Sandstone | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture)</Subject>
        <personalNames>King Ashoka</personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>toranas | reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-75</Accession>
        <Title>Northern Torana (Exterior) at Great Stupa at Sanchi</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: This image shows the carved relief on the Northern Torana (exterior view) at the Great Stupa at Sanchi. | Location created: Madhya Pradesh, India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: Sandstone | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture)</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>toranas | reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-76</Accession>
        <Title>Detail of Scene from Northern Torana (Exterior) at Great Stupa at Sanchi</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: This image shows a detailed scene of the carved relief on the Northern Torana (exterior view) at the Great Stupa at Sanchi. | Location created: Madhya Pradesh, India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: Sandstone | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture)</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>toranas | reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-77</Accession>
        <Title>Yakshi Bracket Figure with Elephants on Torana at Great Stupa at Sanchi</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The sandstone beams across the gateways at the Great Stupa at Sanchi were held up by bracket figures like this, representing female tree spirits called yakshis. In an ancient (pre-Buddhist) Indian fertility rite, beautiful young maidens were said to usher in spring by kicking a tree trunk while breaking off a branch, so as to arouse it into blossoming. The sculpture of these early Buddhist sites includes many such pre-Buddhist symbols. Here, the Shalabhanjika Yakshi serves as a fertility symbol associated with the spirit of the tree and earth to ensure the auspiciousness of the site where the stupa is built. Elephants often symbolize strength and wisdom. | Location created: Madhya Pradesh, India | Date created: c. 150 BCE - 50 CE | Current location: X | Medium: Sandstone | Measurements: X</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>50</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture) | Yakṣī (Hindu deity)</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Sānchi Site (India)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>toranas | reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>1st century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-78</Accession>
        <Title>Birth of the Future Buddha</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: In this carved stone relief, we see Prince Siddartha being born out of his mother's side. Queen Maya, the Buddha's mother, stands beneath a canopy of leaves of a Sala-tree, denoting the Lumbini Forest where the event takes place. She is shown reaching up to break a bough with her right hand, similar in pose to a salabhanjika yakshi, while her left arm passes round the shoulder of her sister, Mahaprajapati, who stretches out a comforting arm across her stomach. To her right stands the god Indra with a nimbus who receives the Infant upon a scarf.  This relief also shows Hellinistic influence on early Buddhist art. | Location created: Gandhara (Pakistan and Afghanistan) | Date created: c. 2nd - 6th century CE | Current location: X | Medium: Schist | Measurements: h. 26.5 cm</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>600</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture)</Subject>
        <personalNames>Queen Maya | Gautama Buddha</personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Gandhara (Pakistan and Afghanistan)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>6th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>16.8531-79</Accession>
        <Title>Bodhisattva</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: Under the Kushans, there are numerous representations of richly adorned, princely Bodhisattvas all in a Greco-Buddhist style and pose, such as this sculpture. The Bodhisattvas, characteristic of the Mahayana form of Buddhism, are represented under the traits of Kushan princes, completed with their canonical accessories.  | Location created: Peshwar Region | Date created: c. 2nd - 6th century CE | Current location: Seattle Art Museum | Medium: Dark grey schist | Measurements: h. 45 in</Description>
        <Source>Artstor</Source>
        <Date_Created>600</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist art and symbolism | Relief (Sculpture) | Bodhisattvas in art</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre>reliefs (sculptures)</Genre>
        <Century>6th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
        
        
        
        
        
    </row>
</root>